uimn.org 2011-12-31

# Privacy Policy for State of Minnesota Department of Employment and Economic Development (DEED) website

**Privacy Statement for the  
Minnesota Department of Employment and Economic Development Websites ***

The Minnesota Department of Employment and Economic Development (DEED) websites provide an electronic means for accessing information about the programs and services available through DEED. Web pages are continually under development as we attempt to keep our content as current as possible.

DEED is committed to protecting the privacy of users in accordance with [Minn. Stat. § 13](https://www.revisor.leg.state.mn.us/statutes/?id=13), the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act; this privacy statement explains how. We reserve the right to alter our privacy policy as business needs require. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this website in a timely manner.

**Information Collected and Used  
**If you visit our sites to browse, read, and/or download information, the following information is collected and used.

We use "cookies," the small text files that our websites place on your computer's hard drive to collect information about your activities on the sites. We collect and store the Internet Protocol (IP) address for the computer you used to access the sites; the identification of your browser software and operating system; the date and time you accessed the sites; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our sites.

We use this information to measure the number of visitors to the different sections of our sites and to help us make our sites more useful. We cannot and do not associate any of this information with individual persons, distribute this information to any third parties, or use it in any manner other than for statistical analysis in improving our sites for visitors. This information is classified as private or nonpublic. We retain this information indefinitely.

If you choose to identify yourself by sending us an e-mail or completing our online forms, we use the personally identifying information to process or respond to your request. If you complete an online form, the information you provide is up to you. However, if you do not provide certain information, such as your name, it may be impossible for us to respond to your request.

DEED websites use Secure Socket Layering (SSL) to encrypt data on our forms that request or require private data; SSL technology is the industry standard for secure online transactions. We may retain this information in our files, either in electronic form or hardcopy. Some of this information is public data under the Minnesota Government Data Practices Act.

Information e-mailed to us via the Internet is not secure and could be intercepted and read by others. We recommend that you not use e-mail to send us private or sensitive data about yourself or others unless the data is encoded or encrypted. Also, users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult and may be subject to public access.

**Your Rights as the Subject of Government Data  
**The Minnesota Government Data Practices Act governs your right to see and know about the data that government entities collect, keep, or can release about you:

  * All data DEED collects are public and can be seen by anyone unless classified as private or not public by state or federal law.
  * You have the right to know what data is collected about you and to view all public or private data about yourself at no cost or be charged a reasonable fee for copies.
  * You have the right to have the meaning of data explained to you in a way you understand.

DEED will acknowledge and respond to every request it receives for access to collected data in an appropriate and prompt manner. Learn more at Data Practices & Your Right to Information.

**Disclaimer of Endorsement  
**Our websites may contain links to other public or private organizations. DEED does not guarantee the accuracy of the information on other organizations' web pages that we are linked to, and DEED is not responsible for the privacy policies or content of such websites. Links to any product, process, or service by trade name, trademark, manufacturer, or otherwise does not constitute or imply any endorsement, recommendation, or association with those sites, the material contained therein, or the sponsoring entities by the State of Minnesota, DEED, or any of their employees or contractors.

**Disclaimer of Liability  
**While DEED strives to provide accurate, timely, and comprehensive information, the State of Minnesota, DEED, and their employees or contractors assume no legal liability for the accuracy, completeness, or usefulness of any information, apparatus, product, data, or process disclosed herein and do not represent that use of such information, apparatus, product, data, or process would not infringe on privately owned rights.

**Contact Information  
**If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the data practices of our sites, contact:

Deb Serum  
Data Practices Compliance Official  
Minnesota Department of Employment and Economic Development  
1st National Bank Building  
332 Minnesota Street, Suite E200  
Saint Paul, MN 55101-1351  
Voice: (651) 259-7193; TTY/TTD: (651) 296-3900; E-mail: [Deb.Serum@state.mn.us](mailto:deb.serum@state.mn.us)

* **DEED Websites:**

  * **www.positivelyminnesota.com** (main site)
  * www.focusonability.net
  * www.gwdc.org
  * www.minnesota-china.com
  * www.MinnesotaWorks.net
  * www.mnprospector.com
  * www.mnsilc.org
  * www.uimn.org

Back   Return Home
